MARCELO GOMES DA SILVA

Rua Ruy Camargo, 51 Apt. 13A Zip Code: 05570-170 +55 (11) 98686-8333 marcelo.gs@terra.com.br



PROFILE

Systems analyst, developer and technology enthusiast, working for over ten years with systems development and analysis, creation and maintenance of software (Desktop and Web). Improvements and optimization of pre-existing codes, identification of bottlenecks in the application, creation of new features and improvement of existing ones. I currently participate in the evolution of a system that coded from scratch in COBOL / DB2 technologies for processing and business logic and ASP.NET as a presentation layer - Large system that handles disputes between acquirer and credit card networks (chargeback) - I work in both Mainframe and Web fronts.



EDUCATION

MBA, Technology for Business: AI, Data Science and Big Data | Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul 2019 – 2020

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | Universidade Nove de Julho 2009 – 2010

Associate degree, Specific Formation in Information Systems Management | Universidade Nove de Julho 2007 – 2009



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

TechLead – Senior Systems Analyst | Rede (Grupo Itaú-Unibanco)

2014 – ATUAL (6 years e 5 months)

Analysis and systems development

Responsible for Chargeback, Range Management, Unreconciled Transactions and Withdrawal flows projects.

Technical leadership of the internal and external team [Software Factory]

Vision and Maintenance of systems architecture

Responsible for the Technical Debits of the team

Engagement of team members in agile methodologies.

Developer Analyst | Nestlé (allocation by Talent Group)

2013 – 2014 (11 months)

Developer Analyst focusing on .NET projects (C # and VB.NET) with SQL Server 2008 database.

Supporting global and local applications, the solutions follow all ITIL principles where they must submitted to a Change & Release process.

The dynamism of the information is great since the global application aims to serve all the markets served in the world.

Local applications that mostly supported for all of Latin America.

All development is WEB.

Main activities:

- Analyze and implement improvements and bug fixes that already exist in the system.
- Present improvements in the development and flow of tools
- Create Application Documentation process

Senior Developer | Confitec – Confiança e Tecnologia

2013 – 2013 (3 Meses)

Programmer focused on VB6 and SQL Server for large projects in the insurance industry (Banco do Brasil and Mapfre). I developed improvement projects in the entire insurance system of Banco do Brasil / Mapfre. The improvements were in performance in VB6 and rewriting procedures in SQL Server 2008.

Also part of this project was a migration to SQL Server 2012.

Developer Analyst | Totalsys Tecnologia

2007 – 2013 (5 Anos e 9 Meses)

Performance of software development activities (improvements and maintenance) (Desktop and Web) in several languages including:

- Visual Basic 6
- SOL (MS SOL Server)
- Python

Any language that was necessary for the full functioning of the system; Development in projects with technologies:

.NET (C #, ASP.NET, MVC 2) and experimenting with the PostgreSQL Database Responsible for the company's experimentation area.



SKILLS

- Software development
- Agile methodologies
- Scrum
- Kanban
- Business requirements
- Technical leadership

- Chargeback System (Dispute)
- PCI DSS
- C#/ASP.NET
- Python
- Data base
- Excel



UNIVERSITY EXTENSION

Professional, Emotional and Technological Skills for Times of Change - Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul 2020

Digital Culture and Innovation - Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul 2019

How to Achieve Professional Goals and Financial Goals - Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul

Continuous Development Mindset - PUCRS - Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul 2019

Productivity, Time Management and Purpose - PUCRS - Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul

2019

2019

Fundamentals, Elaboration and Analysis of Projects | Project management - Faculdade de Educação São Luís 2019



CERTIFICATE

CertiProf

- Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate (SFPC)
- Kanban Foundantion (KIKF)™
- CertiProf Continuous Learner
- DevOps Essentials Professional Certificate

SCRUMstudy - Accreditation Body for Scrum and Agile

Scrum Fundamentals Certified

Itcerts Inc

- Big Data Analyst Certificate
- Big Data Foundation Certificate
- Cloud Security Foundation Certificate
- Data Governance Foundation Certificate
- Data Science Essentials Certificate
- Data Security Specialist Certificate
- InfoSec Foundation Certificate
- Information Security Analyst Certificate
- Information Security Policy Foundation Certificate
- Vulnerability Management Foundation Certificate